<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
<row Id="78" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="80" CreationDate="2016-01-12T21:30:33.083" Score="11" ViewCount="1003" Body="&lt;p&gt;I made a test print for a small gear (~ 1.5 inches in diameter) a few months ago, with a hole through the center. On the first try, the filament (ABS) fused to the print bed, meaning that I had to spend ten minutes scraping off material to loosen it. One solution to this is to use painter's tape spread across the print bed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This yielded a good print during the next run. The problem with this method was that some of the tape subsequently fused to the backside of the gear; it was so tight that I had to discard the prototype. Multiple varieties of tape made no difference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to continue using this tape without having it fuse to the filament?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="61" LastEditorUserId="61" LastEditDate="2016-01-13T23:14:17.547" LastActivityDate="2016-02-22T22:29:01.050" Title="How can I stop my print bed tape from sticking to the filament?" Tags="&lt;abs&gt;&lt;filament&gt;&lt;maintenance&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" />
<row Id="215" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2016-01-13T20:59:21.280" Score="18" ViewCount="21553" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've occasionally had issues with excess filament residue getting stuck to the print bed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://3dprinting.stackexchange.com/questions/78/how-can-i-stop-my-print-bed-tape-from-sticking-to-the-filament&quot;&gt;There are ways to prevent this&lt;/a&gt;, but sometimes even these precautions aren't enough. Over time, residue can build up. I've observed this in some printers, though not others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there any techniques to best clean print beds? In the past, I've used various typical cleaning supplies, with different degrees of success. However, I don't know if this will lead to damage to the printer over time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The printer I'm using has a glass print bed, which I occasionally partially cover with blue painter's tape during printing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="61" LastEditorUserId="61" LastEditDate="2016-01-14T21:29:33.530" LastActivityDate="2017-09-19T18:50:09.917" Title="How can I best clean the print bed after a print?" Tags="&lt;maintenance&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="4" FavoriteCount="1" />
<row Id="1446" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1444" CreationDate="2016-06-29T11:14:00.893" Score="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;One possible solution is to &quot;park&quot; the hotend on the print bed as it is heating up. The bed blocks the nozzle, and prevents ooze from coming out. If any does come up, it tends to stick to the bed, not to the nozzle. You can do this by including an appropriate &lt;code&gt;G1&lt;/code&gt; command in your start G-code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastActivityDate="2016-06-29T11:14:00.893" CommentCount="0" />
<row Id="2892" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2894" CreationDate="2016-10-14T00:54:25.423" Score="5" ViewCount="145" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a QIDI Tech 1. It has a heated bed, and a cooling fan attachment. Whenever I print without a raft, the first inch or two of material laid down does not adhere to the bed, but the rest of the first layer is flawless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have tried speeding up and slowing down the first layer walls, but the problem remains. It also seemed to get a little worse when slower. I also tried not turning on the cooling fan for a bit to see if maybe the material was cooling too quickly, but that had zero effect on it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'd like to avoid using tape and other methods since the rest of the print is perfect, and the bed already has a material on it to aid adhesion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What else can I try to prevent the dragging for the start of the print?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4548" LastActivityDate="2016-10-14T01:12:33.650" Title="Poor adhesion only for first couple of inches" Tags="&lt;pla&gt;&lt;adhesion&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" />
<row Id="3439" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3103" CreationDate="2017-01-19T19:56:33.797" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;A thermal image of my aluminum heated bed does not show hotspots, although the edges are cooler than the majority of the center.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Nh3Uu.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Nh3Uu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hyrel Hotbed Thermal Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4922" LastEditorUserId="4762" LastEditDate="2017-02-16T12:00:41.633" LastActivityDate="2017-02-16T12:00:41.633" CommentCount="2" />
<row Id="3487" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="3490" CreationDate="2017-01-29T14:39:53.090" Score="3" ViewCount="352" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a Wanhao Duplicator i3 v2 (A.K.A. Maker Select, Cocoon Create).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My extruder got clogged: I noticed that it wasn't extruding, so I stopped my print, removed the fan, heatsink and the extruder motor and I saw that the clog is at the heater block level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a what I have:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/uDyF2.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/uDyF2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blocked extruder - no flash&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/iL1mQ.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/iL1mQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blocked extruder - flash&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there is some PLA clogged at the very beginning of the 1.75mm hole in the extruder block.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can see there is something white inside (a stone? something that is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; PLA?). I tried to heat up the extruder to 250°C and pushing with an hex tool but the block did not move. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I solved a lot of clogged nozzle issues with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://printrbot.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/202100554-How-to-Unclog-the-Hotend-The-Cold-Pull&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;cold pull method&lt;/a&gt;, it always worked like a charm, this time I tried too but as a result the PLA filament broke and the &quot;stone&quot; is still there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know if there is a way to unclog the extruder in this situation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do I have to change it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="5317" LastEditorUserId="4762" LastEditDate="2017-01-31T08:56:09.020" LastActivityDate="2017-01-31T16:20:08.727" Title="How to unclog a clogged extruder?" Tags="&lt;filament&gt;&lt;extruder&gt;&lt;pla&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
<row Id="3555" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3554" CreationDate="2017-02-09T14:07:31.083" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Repeating patterns like that usually stem from issues in the Z axis.  This is likely caused by bent screws which in turn cause the X axis to move around.    Are the top of the threaded rods constrained?  If they are, an easy fix may just be to let the top of the threaded rods float around by removing the constraint.  Most Prusa i3's use 5mm threaded rod for the screws and 8mm smooth rod, does your printer use the same setup?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your printer has 8mm (or 5/16&quot;) threaded rod you could try to get some that are straight or the better solution would be to get the 5mm threaded rods and just print adapters to hold the 5mm nut inside the trap.  This would require new couplers (aluminum or rubber/plastic hose), 5mm threaded rods, nuts, adapters (printed) and a small change to the firmware.  This works because the 5mm rod is more flexible than the 8mm smooth rod and less likely to force the carriage around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you already have the 5mm threaded rod/8mm smooth rod then I would look to make sure your X axis is tight and does not move around on the Z axis smooth rods.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would be easier to point out if you include a picture of your printer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edit:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your printer is the mElephant from Makeblock then I would try removing the bearings at the top that constrain the threaded rods and try the print again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="233" LastEditorUserId="233" LastEditDate="2017-02-09T14:39:37.070" LastActivityDate="2017-02-09T14:39:37.070" CommentCount="5" />
<row Id="4487" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="4502" CreationDate="2017-08-13T15:21:25.787" Score="3" ViewCount="124" Body="&lt;p&gt;For personal usage, indoor, I'm doing some experiments with following lamp (v0.1):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/SrEhy.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/SrEhy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lamp is a led bulb enclosed in a methacrylate tube and with a 3D printed finish at the top using PLA (my first 3d print ;-).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In some www pages (by example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifx.com/blogs/the-latest/19032975-how-hot-are-led-light-bulbs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) I've read that the led buld radiator can reach 90º C. Experimentally, the methacrylate and the PLA feels only slightly hot, I suppose around 40ºC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to www info, PLA has a melting point of 150ºC, far from this usage, but a continuous operative temperature of only 40ºC ( !? this made 3d printing unable in a country as my own one, where ambient in summer is around 40ºC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, my question, is PLA a valid material for this application? If not, some other one better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8103" LastEditorUserId="8884" LastEditDate="2018-08-06T08:10:44.563" LastActivityDate="2018-08-06T08:10:44.563" Title="PLA continuous operative temperature" Tags="&lt;pla&gt;&lt;print-material&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
<row Id="4600" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4597" CreationDate="2017-09-09T14:34:53.580" Score="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;In my case, I had a bad resistor on my board. R41 had only 2.2 k&amp;Omega; instead of 4.7. I replaced it and everything works now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8343" LastEditorUserId="8343" LastEditDate="2018-07-16T07:34:43.243" LastActivityDate="2018-07-16T07:34:43.243" CommentCount="3" />
<row Id="5390" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="5460" CreationDate="2018-02-03T20:04:02.017" Score="1" ViewCount="32" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeetech.com/wiki/index.php/Geeetech_G2_%26_G2s_pro&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;geeetech g2s pro&lt;/a&gt; and when I request to print something, the extruder motor doesn't move (it is connected on the board), therefore, the printer prints some kind of imaginary object. I cannot ask Repetir host to extrude it as prevents moving when the extruder is cold, and when it is hot all the repetier host does is moving the header up. Is there a way a could test these motors without needing a hot extruder?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here you have a picture of it, maybe it is upside down.&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/TFWe5.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/TFWe5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;motor&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9830" LastActivityDate="2018-02-10T16:55:24.193" Title="Extruder driver not working" Tags="&lt;motor&gt;&lt;extruder-driver&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>